[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[정품을 보호하는 것은 우리 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설 '천향인' 각색 작품]
[Episode 10]
[제10화]
Riyan!
일염
Let them go!
그들을 놓아주십시오
If you want spirit energy, take mine.
영기를 원하신다면 제가 드리겠습니다
Use this useless disciple as a vessel
이 폐제제라를 노정으로 삼아
to get all the fox spirit's cultivation,
여우 요괴 수위를 모두 거둬들이면
and I'll be the strongest in the Central Plains.
내가 중토의 제일인자가 될 것인데
Then I won't need your little spirit energy.
네 따위 영기가 아쉬울 것 같으냐?
Beast!
짐승 같은 놈
He's your disciple!
그는 당신 제자잖아요
When his meridians shattered, and his life faded,
그가 예전에 경맥이 모두 끊어지고 기식마저 끊어졌을 때
I kept him alive with my spirit energy.
내가 영기로 목숨을 이어준 것이다
Today, he is repaying my kindness.
오늘은 스승의 은혜를 갚는 셈이라 치지
Once I've got all his spirit energy,
내가 그의 영기를 모두 거둔 뒤
I'll send you two to death.
너희 둘을 저승으로 보내주마
This tomboy won't escape, either.
물론 저 남장 아이도 말이다
Shanhua.
형님
Shanhua, it's Xiuyuan.
형님, 저 수원입니다
Xiuyuan.
수 원
My name is Lu Shanhua, your guard.
저는 노산화라고 하고, 당신의 시위입니다
From this day forward,
앞으로
I'll protect you with my life.
목숨을 걸고 지켜주겠습니다
Continue.
계속
We've agreed
약속한 거다
to roam the world together,
우린 함께 세상을 유람하고
find a secluded place,
아무도 없는 곳을 찾아
and never live as fugitives again.
더 이상 도망치는 나날을 보내지 않기로 하자
Shanhua.
형님
Xiuyuan, kill me.
수원아, 날 죽여라
Hurry, end my life.
어서 나를 죽여라
Shanhua, don't give up. I'll save you.
형님, 포기하지 마십시오, 제가 구해드릴게요
Finally, I wield
여우 요괴의 힘
the fox spirit's power.
내가 드디어 여우 요괴의 힘을 얻었구나
The demonic energy!
마기다
Who are you?
너 누구냐?
Where are my spirit roots?
내 영근은 어디 갔지?
Demon!
마물이구나
Shanhua,
형님
wake up.
정신 차려보세요
It's Xiuyuan.
저 수원이에요
All has come to an end.
모든 게 끝났습니다
It's over.
모두 끝났습니다
Shanhua.
형님
Shanhua, wake up.
정신 차려보세요, 형님
Kill me.
나를 죽여라
Just kill me!
나를 죽여라
Hurry up and do it!
당장 나를 죽여란 말이다
Xiuyuan,
형제여
take care.
몸 잘 챙겨라
Lifei!
려비
Lifei, come on, get up.
려비, 자, 일어나
Are you alright?
괜찮아?
I'm fine.
괜찮습니다
I'll kill him!
저자를 죽여버릴 것이다
Take me away.
저를 데리고 가주십시오
Alright.
그래
Master, why can't I make friends?
사부님, 왜 친구를 사귀면 안 되나요?
Countless wicked folk are out in the world.
세상엔 나쁜 사람들이 많다
What if you befriend someone untrustworthy
만일 믿지 못할 친구를 사귀었다가
and lose your life?
목숨을 잃으면 어떡하냐?
Master,
사부님
you really are a jinx.
참 까마귀 입이시네요
You should never have saved him back then.
애초에 그를 구하지 말았어야 했다
Blame my soft-hearted nature.
내가 마음이 약했었지
From now on, stay far away from him.
앞으로 그를 멀리해야 한다
Cut all ties with him.
다시는 엮이지 마라
Learn your lesson after suffering such losses.
손해를 보았으면 교휸으로 삼아야 된다
I shall return to nurture my primordial spirit.
나는 원신을 기르러 가겠다
Take care of yourself.
스스로 정리하거라
He hurt you so badly,
그가 너를 그렇게 크게 다치게 했는데
yet you risked everything to save me.
너는 목숨을 걸고 나를 구해줬어
Do you think I saved you?
내가 너를 구했다고 생각하느냐?
Enough of this. Stay sharp from now on,
됐다, 앞으로 영리하게 굴고
and protect yourself.
네 목숨부터 지켜야 한다
Hurry back to the academy.
어서 서원으로 돌아가라
Understood.
그래
Lifei!
려비
I knew I'd find you here.
역시 여기 있었군
Why did you leave without a word?
왜 아무 말도 없이 떠났느냐?
Nothing.
아무 일도 없습니다
Just wanted to take a look back here.
그냥 돌아와서 한번 보고 싶었습니다
Blame me for being set on recruiting Lei Xiuyuan,
내가 뇌수원을 끌어들인 탓에
and I nearly got you killed.
네가 목숨을 잃을 뻔하게 했구나
I was so foolish that I
제가 어리석었습니다
even planned to help him save Lu.
그를 도와서 사람을 구하겠다고 생각했었는데
Honestly…
참
He hid his true identity so deeply
너무 깊숙이 숨어 있었으니
and even risked his life.
목숨을 걸고 시험하지 않으면
We'd never see through it.
발견하기 어려웠을 거다
After all my schemes and posturing,
사람을 속이고 다녔더니
I never expected to be tricked.
남들의 계책에 말려들었네요
It's fine. We're even on favors and debts. Strangers from now on.
괜찮습니다, 은혜와 원한 모두 청산했으니 앞으로는 남이죠
Clean and simple.
시원하게 끝났네요
Lifei,
려비야
would you go to the Yue State with me?
나와 월국으로 돌아갈 생각은 없느냐?
Time to return to the academy.
서원으로 돌아가야 됩니다
I need to find my master
사부님도 찾아야 되고
and stay alive.
계속 살아가야 되잖아요
We've been away for too long.
이번에 나온 지도 꽤 오래됐습니다
Lifei, you've been back for days.
려비, 돌아온 지도 벌써 며칠인데
Why only practice without saying a word?
왜 수련만 하고 말 한마디도 없습니까?
Where's Xiuyuan?
수원은요?
Lifei, have you seen Xiuyuan?
려비, 수원 본 적 없습니까?
You went to Xingzheng Hall together.
같이 성정관에 갔었잖아요
I asked Tongzhou, but he hasn't seen him.
동주한테 물어봤지만 못 봤다던데요
Could anything go wrong with him?
무슨 일이 생긴 건 아닐까요?
Ask someone else.
다른 사람한테 물어보십시오
Wait.
아니
Lifei.
려비
What are you doing back here?
뭐 하러 돌아왔느냐?
I need to talk to you.
할 얘기가 있다
We have nothing to say. Leave.
우린 할 말 없으니 가라
Sorry.
미안하다
I must save Shanhua.
형님을 구해야만 했다
No need to apologize.
사과할 것 없다
I was blind and foolish.
내가 눈이 어둡고 어리석었을 뿐
I knew you held other plans, yet I trusted you.
네가 다른 마음을 품고 있는 걸 알면서도 너를 믿었었다
Quit putting on that miserable act.
너도 이제 불쌍한 척 연기할 필요가 없다
Henceforth, we are strangers,
앞으로 우리 서로 모르는 사이로 지내자
without any ties between us.
다시는 얽히지 말고
Lei Xiuyuan.
뇌수원
Come with me.
이리 오시오
I'm sorry.
미안하오
What good are empty apologies?
미안하다고 해봤자 무슨 소용인가?
We treated you with sincerity, yet you tricked us.
우리가 그토록 믿었었는데 줄곧 계책만 꾸몄다니
If Zhenyunzi had succeeded,
진운자가 정말 뜻을 이루었다면
what would have become of Lifei?
려비는 어찌할 셈이었소?
What about me?
나는?
And what about Xuanshanzi?
우리 큰 아버님은 어찌할 셈이었소?
Let's fight!
칼을 드시오
Don't go too far in duels. You might kill each other.
수련도 정도껏 해야지, 사람 죽어
Talk this through calmly, alright?
말로 하면 될 걸
If you lose control again, you'll be expelled from the academy.
다음에 또 이러면 서원에서 쫓겨날 각오해야 돼
Xiuyuan, you're careful. My chicken has grown up.
수원아, 네가 세심하잖느냐, 구구닭이 다 커서
I need someone to build a coop for it.
사형이 마침 닭장 만들 사람을 찾고 있었다
Could you help me? Let's go.
와서 좀 도와줄래?
Go.
가자
Let's go.
자, 가자
Come out.
나와라
If you can't stand the sight of me,
나를 보기 싫다면
pretend I'm not here at all.
나를 없는 사람 취급해도 좋다
Do you think trailing after me
네가 계속 날 따라다니면
will make me forgive you?
내가 널 용서할 거라 생각해?
I don't ask for your forgiveness.
용서는 바라지 않았다
I only want to make amends.
그저 보상하고 싶었다
Make amends?
보상?
Suppose you get me killed,
내가 정말 죽었더라면
would you cry at my grave?
내 무덤 앞에 와서 눈물만 흘릴 셈이었나?
I'm sorry. I thought, as I did it myself,
미안하다, 내가 직접 손을 쓰면
I wouldn't hurt you so badly.
네가 크게 다치지 않을 줄 알았다
But I never expected Zhenyunzi's scheme.
하지만 난 진운자가...
You thought he only wanted Riyan
그가 일염만 원할 거라 생각했고
and that you could protect me.
네가 나를 지켜줄 수 있을 거라 생각했어?
Who could you protect?
대체 누구를 지킬 수 있는데?
Lu is important to you, I know.
노 선배가 네 가족인 건 맞다
But Riyan also means a lot to me.
하지만 일염도 내가 아끼는 자다
Why did you use me and sacrifice Riyan?
왜 나를 이용하고 일염을 희생시키려 했어?
Why deceive me over and over?
왜서 나를 속였어?
You planned every step.
한 걸음씩 계책을 꾸몄고
You risked yourself at Hongyang Hall
홍양전에서 목숨 걸고 나를 구해줬고
and Kept Zong Quan from hurting me.
종권 부하들 앞에서 나를 지켜주었고
What a clever pity play.
참 대단한 고육계였네
You're ruthless
정말 독하군
enough to be cruel to yourself and me.
나한테도, 너한테도 말이다
I've got nothing to compare to that.
정말 부끄러울 따름이군
What's done is done.
흘러간 물은 다시 주워담을 수 없다
All these gestures to make it up to me now
네가 지금 하는 온갖 보상하려는 행동은
are to make yourself feel better.
그저 네가 마음 편해지게 하려는 것뿐
I'll never trust you again.
다시는 너를 믿지 않을 거다
At least let me do one thing for you.
적어도 너를 위해 뭐라도 하게 해주라
No need.
싫다
Save yourself the embarrassment.
괜히 매달리지 말거라
Mr. Mo,
선생님
please break the Fragrance Bond.
천향인을 풀어주십시오
Why?
이유가 무엇이냐?
All gatherings must come to an end.
세상에서는 끝나지 않는 연회는 없는 법
We're bound to part sooner or later.
언젠가는 헤어질 사이인데
No point keeping it active anymore.
천향인을 잡고 있어도 소용없을 것 같습니다
Life is fleeting.
인생은 짧으니
The encounters and companions of our youth
젊은 나이에 겪은 일들, 만난 사람들은
are all precious treasures.
모두 소중한 법이다
Wouldn't it be a pity to cast them aside easily?
쉽게 버리기엔 너무 아깝지 않느냐?
♪It's me, blinded by longing♪
♪내 눈에 병이 생긴 건지♪
♪Every glance lands on you♪
♪눈앞에 온통 너만 가득하네♪
♪Fire and water clash, yet we cling inseparably♪
♪물불은 어울릴 수 없는데 끈끈히 붙어있네♪
♪Lotus broken, threads still bind us♪
♪연은 끊어져도 실은 서로를 잇고♪
♪My heart calm till you stir storms and rain♪
♪내 마음 잔잔한테 넌 비를 내리게 하네♪
♪You are my destined rival♪
♪넌 나의 숙적♪
♪Winters pass, springs come; bound for lifetimes♪
♪봄이 오고 생사 함께할 운명은♪
♪Fate ties me to you♪
♪너에게 달렸네♪
♪Mountains, rivers, lakes and seas♪
♪산과 바다를 가리지 않고♪
♪I follow no one but you♪
♪너만 따라가리♪
♪Bitterness brews sweet bliss♪
♪쓴 아픔 속 달콤함을♪
♪Drained in one sip♪
♪빚어 마시고♪
♪Love and feud balance out, I'm yours alone♪
♪사랑과 원한을 상쇄하고 너를 마음에 새기네♪
♪Fated foes, fate plays tricks♪
♪숙명의 적인데 하늘이 맺어♪
♪You complete my five elements♪
♪오행에는 너만 빠졌네♪
♪Burning love, unbridled hatred♪
♪사랑은 뜨겁고 미움은 시원하니♪
♪They suit each other well♪
♪서로 어울리네♪
♪If you don't leave, I'll never abandon you♪
♪네가 떠나지 않는다면 나 또한 포기하지 않으리♪
♪We'll dwell in mortal dust♪
♪이렇게 속세에서 끝까지♪
♪Stay side by side till the end♪
♪함께하리♪
Break it off. All is hollow affection.
풀어주십시오, 다 가식일 뿐입니다
Nothing is worth clinging to.
아쉬울 것 없습니다
What exactly happened?
대체 무슨 일이 일어났었느냐?
Nothing. I've just seen the truth.
아무 일도 아닙니다, 그냥 깨달았을 뿐입니다
Fine.
그래
But you three must stand united to break it.
다만 천향인을 풀려면 세 사람이 한마음이 되어야 한다
Any missteps will hurt your spirit meridians.
조금만 잘못해도 영맥이 손상될 수 있으니
Discuss with the other two and come to me.
그들과 상의한 뒤에 다시 찾아오거라
I've only brought ruin on myself.
정말 돌 들어 자기 발등 찍는 격이군
I never expected
네가
you to manage
저 아이를
to bring him back unharmed.
살려서 데리고 돌아올 능력이 있을 줄은 몰랐네
Qingqiu truly holds wondrous powers.
청구에는 역시 신통한 힘이 가득하군
Qingqiu breeds extraordinary souls.
청구는 확실히 뛰어난 인물이 모이는 곳입니다
No wonder my senior brother
아니면 저희 사형이
is such a peerless,
어찌 하늘이 내린 재능을 갖추고
elegant genius.
그토록 멋지시겠습니까?
Do you agree, Mr. Hu?
그렇지 않나요, 선생님
Well said.
맞는 말이다
So you do know my senior brother.
역시 저희 사형을 아시는군요
Where is he?
제 사형, 어디에 계십니까?
How would I know?
내가 어찌 알겠느냐?
With thousands of disciples at Wuyue Court,
무월정에 제자가 수천 명 되는데
there is no way to tell him from the rest.
누가 네 사형인지 어찌 알겠느냐?
What court? Wuyue Court.
무월정이요?
Give up hope. You'll never find him.
마음 접거라, 넌 그를 찾지 못할 거다
Tongzhou, what does this line mean?
전하, 이건 무슨 뜻입니까?
This one?
이거?
When the heart is unpurified, desires must be cast away.
마음이 맑지 못하면 욕망이 되롭히는 법
Like this.
이렇게요?
It means you must cast aside distracting thoughts.
즉 전잡한 생각을 버려야 한다는 뜻이다
While cultivating qi,
연기할 때
focus your mind on your breath
호흡에 의식을 집중하고
and banish all stray thoughts.
잡념을 모두 버려야
Only then will you make progress.
경지에 다다를 수 있다
Once you fully grasp the practice,
모든 원리를 통달하게 되면
even without controlling your breath,
호흡에 신경 쓰지 않아도
the vital qi will naturally fill your dantian.
자연스레 기관단전의 효과를 얻을 수 있다
You'll make it. I believe in you.
너는 할 수 있을 거다, 난 너를 믿는다
Sit down.
앉으세요
Speak. What happened at Xingzheng  Hall?
성정관에서 대체 무슨 일이 일어났습니까?
Why do you avoid Xiuyuan as if he were a plague?
왜 수원을 귀신 본 것처럼 피합니까?
Nothing much. We've parted ways.
아무 일도 아닙니다, 그냥 헤어졌을 뿐입니다
We won't stay together from now on.
앞으로 같이 다닐 일 없습니다
You claim it's nothing?
아무 일도 아니라니
You once swore to live and die together.
생사를 함께한 벗인데
Can't just split up so easily.
어찌 쉽게 헤어질 수 있습니까?
Once we graduate, we'll go our separate ways.
서원 수업이 끝나면 모두 각자의 길을 가게 될 겁니다
With so many immortal sects,
세상에 선문이 얼마나 많은데
Tongzhou will head to Xingzheng Hall,
동주 전하는 성정관으로 갈 거고
and I to Wuyue Court.
저는 무월정으로 갈 거고
As for Lei Xiuyuan,
뇌수원은
he can go wherever he pleases.
가고 싶은 곳으로 가겠지요
We're bound to part sooner or later.
언젠가는 헤어질 사이니
Better split early than drag it out.
일찍 헤어지는 게 낫잖아요
Better split early?
일찍 헤어지는 게 낫다고요?
Lifei, why must you go to Wuyue Court?
려비, 왜 무월정에 가려 하는 겁니까?
There are clues about my master.
무월정에 제 사부님 단서가 있어서요
Besides, Qin and Yue, who visited last time,
게다가 저번에 진 사형과 악 사저가 왔을 때
seemed really kind.
사람들이 좋아 보였어요
I feel like you're hiding something from me.
무언가를 숨기는 것 같은데
Quit talking about me. What about you?
제 얘기는 그만하고
Where will you and Changyue go?
가림과 창원은 어디로 갈 겁니까?
I don't know.
저도 모르겠습니다
I'm inferior to Ye in sword skills
검술은 오라버니보다 못하고
and to Changyue in spirit art.
법술도 언니보다 뒤떨어져
I'm afraid we'll take separate paths.
아마 언젠가는 헤어져야 할 것 같습니다
Don't sell yourself short.
왜 자기 자신을 낮춥니까?
I heard you learned artifact crafting under Mr. Mo.
묵 선생님따라 연기의 술법을 배우셨다면서요
That's a fine skill.
그것만 해도 충분히 좋은데
I've only picked up the basics.
아직 겉할기만 배웠을 뿐입니다
There's a long journey ahead.
앞으로 갈 길은 아직 멀어요
Exactly, the future stretches far.
맞습니다, 아직 갈 길이 머니
Leave future matters for later.
앞으로의 일은 나중에 얘기해요
For now, push all worries aside,
지금은 아무 생각도 하지 말고
study hard,
열심히 수련해
and strive to enter our dream immortal sects soon.
가고 싶은 선문에 가도록 노력해야죠
Okay.
좋아요
When you suddenly headed to Xingzheng Hall,
갑자기 성정관에 갔을 때
I guessed it was about Lu.
노산화 형님과 관련된 일일 거라 생각했소
Years ago, my mother sent him to protect you.
옛날 어머니께서 그를 보내 당신을 지켜주게 하셨소
Is
형님은
he gone?
이미 돌아가신 거요?
I dragged him into this mess.
내가 형님을 지켜주지 못했소
I'm unforgivable.
내 죄는 용서받을 수 없소
Don't blame yourself harshly, Xiuyuan.
수원, 너무 자책하지 마시오
I don't know the full story,
이 일의 전말은 내가 잘 모르지만
but his soul above would
형님은 하늘에서 분명 그대가
definitely want you to be alright.
잘 지내길 바라실 거요
The departed are at peace.
이미 떠나갔으니
What will you do next?
앞으로 무슨 계획이오?
Make amends.
잘못을 갚고
Avenge Shanhua.
형님의 원수를 갚을 거요
Avenge?
원수라니
Who's the culprit?
그 원수가 누군데
Xingzheng Hall or Longming Sanctuary?
성정관, 아니면 용명좌?
You don't need to know.
알 필요 없소
I…
아니
Xiuyuan, Xiuyuan,
수원, 수원
most things
사람 살다 보면
in life are beyond our control.
뜻대로 되지 않는 일이 많소
Now that mistakes have been made,
잘못을 저질렀다 한들
time will eventually heal all rifts.
시간이 흐르면 언젠가 풀릴 날이 올 것이오
Take us, for example.
우리처럼 말이오
Back then,
그때 나는
I could've stopped everything,
이 일을 막을 수 있었는데
yet I let you take my place to face death.
그냥 당신이 대신 죽게 내버려뒀으니
I was wrong, too.
나도 죄가 많소
But now,
하지만 오늘
we can still sit here
이렇게 마음 가라앉히고
and talk calmly together.
얘기할 수 있잖소
By the way, Lifei will join Wuyue Court.
맞다, 려비가 무월정으로 간다고 하오
Wuyue Court?
무월정으로 간다고?
What are you doing here?
왜 왔어?
I'll help you join Wuyue Court.
내가 무월정에 들어가게 도돠주겠다
No need.
필요 없다
I've looked into it.
내가 다 알아봤다
There are only two ways to join Wuyue Court.
무월정에 들어가려면 두 가지 길밖에 없다
First, get recommended by an inner disciple
하나는 내문 제자의 추천을 받고
to join the outer sect.
외문으로 들어가는 것
Second, pass the academy assessment
둘째는 서원 시험을 통과해
and gain an elder's approval
장로의 인정을 받고
to join the inner sect.
내문으로 들어가는 것
But Wuyue Court hasn't recruited
하지만 무월정에는 십여 년째
any inner disciples for over a decade.
내문 제자를 뽑지 않았다
So?
그래서?
So I want to help you.
그래서 내가 널 도와줄 것이다
More hands mean better odds.
사람이 하나 더 있으면 승산도 커지니까
Is having someone who betrayed me
등에 칼 꽂는 사람이 더 생기는 건데
an advantage or a burden?
이게 승산인가 짐인가?
I will never fail you again.
다시는 너를 저버리지 않겠다
That's your own promise.
그건 네 생각일 뿐
Stop following me.
더 이상 따라오지 마라
I won't let go.
나는 포기하지 않을 거다
Wherever you go,
네가 어딜 가든
I'll find you.
내가 꼭 찾으러 가겠다
You're only relying on this, right?
이것에 기대고 있는 거지
You think the Fragrance Bond ties us together,
천향인으로 얽혀 있으니
leaving a chance between us.
가능성이 있다고 생각하는 거야?
I'll break it right now.
그럼 지금 바로 풀어버리지
Let go.
놔
Must you break it?
꼭 풀어야 해?
Yes.
그래
Don't hurt yourself.
자신을 다치게 하지 마
I'll go with you to see Mr. Mo.
내가 묵 선생님 만나러 따라가겠다
Wait.
잠깐
Come with me now.
따라와
Or else,
아니면
don't blame me for being rude.
억지도 데려가겠다
Ms. Lin?
임 선생님
Where did you get this demonic artifact?
어디서 온 마족이냐?
[Shen Jiao, Wanxian Sect]
[만선문 심초]
Who exactly are you?
너 대체 누구냐?
This is a horn of Yecha!
야차의 뿌리를 갖고 있다니
Horn of Yecha?
야차의 뿌리요
The Demon Lord Yecha from the storybook?
설마 책에 나온 마군 야차인가요?
Exactly.
맞다
During the Sea Calamity battle,
옛날 해운 대전 때
the Demon Lord's two horns were chopped off.
마군이 두 뿌리를 베이고
Mr. Shen of the Wanxian Sect in the East Sea took one.
봉해 만선문 심 선생님이 한 쪽을 주워가셨다
With its demonic energy,
이 물건은 마기를 품고 있어
it can command spirits.
요물을 다스릴 수 있다
Word has it that Mr. Shen crafted it into an ornament
듣기로 심 선생님이 장신구로 만드셔
to protect his beloved daughter Jiao.
딸 심초에게 호신용으로 주었다지
Jiao, why are you
심초 아가씨가 변장하고 여기로
here in disguise?
온 목적이 무었인가?
Right.
맞다
I'm Shen Jiao.
내가 바로 심초다
You monster!
요녀야
Where is the real Lin You?
임유는 어디에 있나?
Since you call me a monster,
요녀라고 불렀으면
she's locked deep in my monster lair
당연히 요정굴에 가두고
and tormented, wanting to live yet cannot,
죽고 싶어도 죽지 못하게
wanting to die yet cannot.
괴롭힘 받고 있겠지
Jiao,
심초
don't talk nonsense.
헛소리 하지 마
You'd never do such cruel things.
너는 절대 그럴 사람이 아닌데
Why utter such vicious words?
왜 그런 말을 꺼내는 거야?
Do you think one kiss
네가 나랑 입을 맞췄다고
means you truly know me?
나를 잘 안다고 생각해?
Yanfan,
언범아
escort Jiao to the Disciplinary Pavilion.
먼저 심초 아가씨를 계율각으로 보내
We'll deal with her properly
임유를 찾은 뒤에
once we find Lin You.
다치 벌을 내리겠다
Understood.
예
Xiuyuan,
수원아
step forward.
이리 오거라
You've overcome countless hardships to get here.
너희는 온갖 고난을 다 겪고 여기까지 왔는데
Even if your loved one is gone,
가족들이 곁에 업사다 해도
you must cherish your own life.
자신의 몸을 아껴야 한다
When tough troubles arise later,
앞으로 풀기 힘든 일이 닥치더라도
there'll always be room to turn things around.
회전할 여지가 전혀 없는 건 아니다
Thank you for your guidance.
선생님의 가르침에 감사드립니다
Mr. Zuo,
선생님
Jiao is crafty.
그 요녀가 교활하여
I fear Mr. Mo may be soft-hearted.
묵 선생님께서 마음이 약해지실까 봐
I want to check on them.
가서 살펴보겠습니다
Go ahead.
그래
You'll have to wait here for now.
잠시 여기 있거라
[Disciplinary Pavilion] I'll explain everything to Mr. Zuo.
내가 원장님한테 얘기해보겠다
Because of me, you…
너는 나 때문에...
Quit chattering.
시끄럽다
Either go back to the East Sea with me
나와 동해로 돌아가
and marry me,
혼인하든지
or get lost right now.
아니면 빨리 꺼지든지
One minute you push him to marry you,
혼인하겠다고 하다가
and the next you tell him to get lost.
또 묵 선생님한테 꺼지라고 하다니
What do you want?
대체 무슨 심보냐?
None of your business.
너랑 무슨 상관인데?
If you two hadn't ruined my plan,
너희 둘이 끼어들지 않았으면
I wouldn't have been locked up here.
내가 어찌 여기에 갇혔겠느냐?
You messed up my plan, okay?
분명 네가 내 일을 망친 거잖아
Mr. Mo,
선생님
I want to break the Fragrance Bond.
천향인을 풀고 싶습니다
He agreed too.
그도 동의했고요
One moment, your hearts align,
서로 마음이 통한다고 하다가
and the next, you turn cold to him.
이제와서 또 등을 돌리네
I'd like to ask you.
나도 묻고 싶다
What do you want?
너는 대체 무슨 심보냐?
That's how life works.
사람이라는 건
Pick things up and let them go when needed.
잡을 줄도 알고 놓을 줄도 알아야지
Far better than someone clinging on relentlessly.
질질 매달리는 것보다 낫지
Letting go?
놓기는 무슨
That's just an excuse for cold, faithless folks
정이 얕고 마음이 변덕스러운 놈들이
to seduce and abandon others.
버릴 때 쓰는 핑계일 뿐
Is that not the truth?
그렇지 않느냐?
You said Mr. Mo betrayed you.
말로는 묵 선생님께서 마음을 버렸다는데
Were you two ever together?
설마 함께한 적이 있었느냐?
We were.
당연하지
Three years ago,
3년 전
I found cultivation in the East Sea dull,
동해에서 수련하는 게 따분해서
so I headed to Mount Que alone,
홀로 궐산으로 갔었다
hoping to catch a spirit as my pet.
요수를 잡아 영총으로 삼으려 했는데
Yet I accidentally got poisoned by a monster
부주의하게 요독에 걸려
and nearly lost my life.
죽을 뻔했었다
At that moment,
그때
I knew what love at first sight meant.
나는 비로소 첫눈에 반한다는 게 무엇인지 알았다
Women of the East Sea are bold and free-spirited.
우리 동해 여인들은 원래 호방하고 자유로워
If we fancy someone,
마음에 드는 사람이 있으면
we'll pursue them without hesitation.
주저 없이 다가가 마음을 표현한다
I thought my sincere devotion
나는 서로 마음이 통해
would win mutual affection.
마음을 주고받을 줄 알았는데
Yet the very next day,
다음 날이 되자
he left a letter and vanished,
그는 편지를 남기고 떠나버렸다
telling me he'd report to his mater at Xingzheng Hall,
성정관으로 돌아가 사존께 고한 뒤
and then answer me.
답을 주겠다고 하였다
But once he left,
하지만 그 뒤로
I never heard from him again,
소식이 없었다
so I had to seek him out at Xingzheng Hall.
그래서 나는 성정관으로 찾아갈 수밖에 없었다
Later,
나중에
I found out he'd left the hall
그가 성정관을 떠나
and hidden in Chufeng Academy.
추봉서원에 숨어있다는 걸 알고
That's why I kidnapped Lin You
임유를 납치한 뒤
and snuck into the academy by disguising myself as her.
그녀의 모습으로 변장해 서원에 잠입한 거다
Jiao,
심초
I've let you down.
내가 너를 저버렸다
Just pretend we never crossed paths.
나와 만난 적이 없었다고 여기면 될 거
Why chase after me still?
왜 쫓아왔느냐?
So you did seduce and abandon her.
정말 버림을 받은 거였군
Mo Yanfan,
묵언범
you avoided me,
네가 날 피하는 게
fearing your master Xuanshanzi
네 사부님 현산자가 화를 참지 못하고
would slay me in rage.
나를 죽일까 봐 두려운 거잖아
Let me tell you,
알려주는데
I fear nothing.
나는 두렵지 않다
I know you had your reasons.
네가 어쩔 수 없는 사정이 있다는 건 알지만
But I'm no delicate young lady
나도 그렇게
who fades at the slightest wind.
바람이 불면 흩어지는 연약한 여인은 아니다
Since I hold affection for you,
나 심초가 네게 마음을 바친 이상
as long as I'm alive,
이 한평생
I'll never let go of you
숨이 붙어있는 한
for the rest of my life.
절대 손을 놓지 않을 거다
Why torture yourself?
왜 이렇게 스스로 고통을 자초하느냐?
I bear all hardship willingly,
고통은 내가 알아서 견디니
and I'll not regret it.
죽어도 후회 없다
Jiao,
심초야
Mr. Zuo has sent a letter to the Wanxian Sect.
원장님께서 동해 만선문으로 편지를 보냈으니
Mr. Shen will arrive any day now.
심 선생님께서 곧 도착하길 거다
Even if he comes, it'll change nothing.
아버지가 오신다 한들 소용없다
I will not back down or let go.
나는 물러나지 않을 거고 놓지도 않을 거다
I'm tired
피곤하다
and done talking to all of you.
더 이상 너희와 잡담하기 싫으니
Get out of my sight
너희도 내 앞에서 거슬리지 마라
and leave me alone.
모두 꺼져라
Do you really want to break the Fragrance Bond?
정말 천향인을 풀 것이냐?
If you find that it troubles you,
선생님께서 마음이 복잡하시다면
we may come back in a few days.
며칠 뒤 다시 찾아오겠습니다
My mind is all in chaos today,
오늘 내 마음이 어지러우니
and I have no will to work on it.
도울 마음이 없구나
Besides, you three must come
게다가 이 천향인을 풀려면
together to break the Fragrance Bond.
너희 셋이 함께 와야 한다
Lifei.
려비야
Tongzhou.
전하
I just sensed the Fragrance Bond stir.
방금 천향인이 반응하였는데
Are you alright?
괜찮느냐?
I'm fine.
괜찮습니다
Mr. Mo,
그럼 선생님
we shall take our leave.
저희는 먼저 돌아가겠습니다
Let's go.
가시죠
Are you really alright?
정말 괜찮느냐?
Yes.
괜찮다니깐요
Glad to hear that.
그럼 다행이구나
Why do I keep dreaming of the Demon Lord Yecha?
왜 마군 야차를 꿈에서 보았을까?
Is that demonic energy
그 마기
related to me?
혹시 나와 관련이 있는 건가?
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설 '천향인' 각색 작품]
♪The warmth within my arms♪
♪품안에 남은 온기♪
♪I can no longer hold on to♪
♪이제 붙잡지 못하네♪
♪In the cold night, how can I♪
♪차가운 밤 어찌 다시♪
♪Keep you warm until sunrise?♪
♪해 뜰 때까지 널 안아줄까♪
♪My heartbeat freezes♪
♪심장 소리 굳어버리고♪
♪I can no longer tell you♪
♪더 이상 속내 털어놓지 못해♪
♪Looking you in the eyes, I cannot♪
♪너를 바라보며 그 한마디♪
♪Utter that line♪
♪입 밖으로 꺼내지 못해♪
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪사랑과 미움인 줄 알면서도♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪아픔과 상처 막을 수 없는데♪
♪I still linger on♪
♪아직 그리워하고♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪이 조각조각 추억을 놓지 못해♪
♪Last night's stars cast faint glimmers♪
♪지난 밤 별빛 희미하게 비추던♪
♪But we thought nothing of it♪
♪그땐 그게 평범한 일이라 여겼지♪
♪With a heartbroken cry♪
♪간이 찢어지는 듯 외치며♪
♪I wish you well♪
♪네 평안을 빌어♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪옳고 그름인 줄 알면서도♪
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪어둠과 회색 모두 허무할 뿐♪
♪You're still screaming♪
♪넌 여전히 목이 찢어지도록♪
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪기력 다해 후회 없이 달려가네♪
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stand in its way♪
♪산비가 다가오는데 바람을 막아서고♪
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝에 남긴 짧은 글 두세 줄♪
♪Leaping straight into♪
♪몸을 던져 그♪
♪That heartbreaking past♪
♪간이 찢어지는 지난 날 속으로♪
♪Just to keep you safe♪
♪네 무사함을 위해♪
♪My breath is about to stop♪
♪내 숨이 끊어지려 하고♪
♪Those hands can no longer hold yours♪
♪그 손 더 이상 잡지 못해♪
♪Through the future snow, wind, and fog♪
♪앞으로 펼쳐질 눈비 안개 길을♪
♪Who will be there by your side?♪
♪누가 너와 함께 걸어줄까♪
♪I smile as it ends♪
♪웃으며 막을 내리지만♪
♪Afraid that you might cry for me♪
♪네가 나 때문에 울까 봐 두려워♪
♪Quietly, I turn into a sky lantern♪
♪살금살금 천등으로 변해♪
♪To light your way through the night♪
♪네 야간 길을 밝혀주리♪
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪사랑과 미움인 줄 알면서도♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪아픔과 상처 막을 수 없는데♪
♪I still linger on♪
♪아직 그리워하고♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪이 조각조각 추억을 놓지 못해♪
♪The storm looms, yet I stand in its way♪
♪산비가 다가와도 난 막아서고♪
♪Torn inside, still I burn bright♪
♪간이 찢어져도 후련할 뿐♪
♪With the light from my fingertips♪
♪손끝의 희미한 빛으로♪
♪I build a paradise♪
♪천국 한쪽을 만들어♪
♪To wander with you♪
♪너와 함께 거닐리♪